STEPHEN SANDERLIN

CONTACT



2543 Reuben Boise Rd. Dallas, OR 97338



stephen.sanderlin@gmail.com



(619) 384-8202

EDUCATION

2009

B.A. in Commercial Film Production Brooks Institute - Santa Barbara, CA

SPECIALIZED TRAINING

2020

CompTIA A+ Certification

2005

FEMA Emergency Situation Management

HONORS/AWARDS

Local Broadcasting Award (CAPPIE 2011)

Filmed and edited a Sports and Leisure documentary (Highway 33)

Squad Leader

(United States Army)

Managed 18+ individuals in areas of time management, self-discipline, and communication

PROFILE SUMMARY

I am a proactive and results-driven professional with 12+ years of experience in advanced technology, broadcast media, and operations management. I have established a track record of proven knowledge that has enabled me to manage and collaborate with other professionals to achieve common goals. I am confident that my collective skills will benefit the growth and enhancement of various media and technology companies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Audio/Visual (AV) Manager | 2017 - 2020

Interstate Hotels (Westin San Diego) - San Diego, CA

- Managed the hiring, training, and ongoing development of team members to help drive performance metrics and revenue growth for the hotel
- Arranged local area networks for large groups to ensure that hardware/software systems were in place for special events, conventions, etc.
- Established wired and wireless networks, conducting on-site troubleshooting for multiple devices
- Liaised between internet service providers and guests to troubleshoot connection issues via phone
- Conducted on-site troubleshooting for multiple devices to accommodate guests/event attendees
- Partnered with other managers to ensure seamless coordination of various hotel activities
- Directed a variety of staff management functions, to include scheduling, work assignments, compliance regulation for policies, and operation of various departmental procedures
- Installed and operated various electronic equipment to record, edit, and transmit radio/television programs and other multimedia presentations
- Performed minor repairs and routine cleaning of audio and video equipment
- Observed and evaluated staff performance to ensure consistency and efficiency in operations

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- ✓ Operational Leadership
- ✓ Time Management
- ✓ Relationship Management
- ✓ Hardware Installations
- ✓ Software Installations
- ✓ Technical Support
- ✓ Multimedia Productions
- ✓ Staff Training/Development
- ✓ Conflict Resolution
- ✓ Visual Communication
- ✓ Verbal Communication
- ✓ AV Equipment Operations
- ✓ Windows and Mac
- ✓ Linux and Unix
- ✓ iOS and Android
- ✓ Google

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

President | 2010 - 2020

Stephen Sanderlin Photo and Video - San Diego, CA

- Established a good rapport with various clients to produce photographs that meet their needs
- Maintained a detailed client list to determine the scope of assignments, project locations (studio and/or on location), and needed equipment
- Specialized in architecture, portrait, and aerial photography for individuals and small groups
- Managed the set-up, operation, and maintenance/repair of all photography equipment and computer systems

Media Director/Editor | 2016 - 2019

DCN Media, Inc. - San Diego, CA

- Trained and managed the productivity of company's entire media crew
- Partnered with various directors to compose and frame, and apply various technical aspects to the lighting, lenses, filters, and camera settings
- Oversaw various video broadcast productions, including the set-up and performance of live shots
- Designed and directed studio productions, instructing camera operators on multiple variables and cues for starting and stopping the filming process
- Operated television and motion picture cameras to record scenes for broadcasting and advertising
- Edited videos for broadcast productions, including nonlinear editing